alexandani.com 2019-01-19

# Privacy Policy

###  Categories of Information We Collect 

We collect personally identifiable information through communications with you, or through the Alex and Ani website (our “Website”), whenever you interact with us online. Some examples include: 

  * registering for a shopping account on our Website 
  * requesting that merchandise be sent to you or others or place an order 
  * purchasing products from our Website 

We may also collect personal information about you from other third parties, such as demographic firms, to make our future service and marketing efforts more efficient and personalized for you. We also gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser information, Internet Service Provider (ISP), operating system, date/time stamp and clickstream data. 

###  How We Use Your Information 

We use your personal information that we collect to conduct our business and to provide you with the best possible products, services and experience. To best serve you, we may share your personally identifiable information with service providers that provide support services to us or that help us market our products and services. Service providers, third parties who perform services on our behalf, are contractually restricted from using your information in any manner other than in helping us to provide you with the products and services available from Alex and Ani. We may also, in certain instances, disclose your personally identifiable information when we have reason to believe that it is necessary to identify you, contact you, or bring legal action to protect your rights or the rights of Alex and Ani or others. We may also disclose your personally identifiable information when you ask us to do so or when we believe it is required by law. 

###  U.S. Mobile Alerts Program Policy 

PLEASE READ CAREFULLY. By entering your mobile phone number, you represent that you are at least 13 years of age and that you agree to these terms and conditions which may be amended from time to time. If you do not accept these terms and conditions, do not use the program. If you choose to participate in any Alex and Ani mobile alerts program that may involve the use of text messaging (either sending or receiving), Alex and Ani will not charge you for the text messaging. However, standard text messaging rates will apply to each text message sent or received as provided in your wireless rate plan (contact your carrier for pricing plans and details). 

###  Mobile Terms & Conditions | Mobile Alerts 

1\. You may subscribe to receive Alex and Ani Mobile Alerts sent to your mobile phone by texting "JOIN" to 95902. Consent to receive text messages is not required to make a purchase of any Alex and Ani goods. 

2\. You must be 13 years of age or older to participate in the Alex and Ani mobile text program. 

3\. By participating in the Alex and Ani mobile text program, and signing up for mobile offers and text updates, you consent to receive future recurring automated marketing text messages to the mobile number provided from or on behalf of Alex and Ani. You also acknowledge that your agreement to receive these messages is not required as a condition of purchase. 

4\. Message and data rates may apply. All charges are billed by and payable to your mobile service provider. Alex and Ani does not charge you for sending or receiving text messages to or from 95902. 

5\. If you would like to be removed from the Alex and Ani mobile text program, text STOP to 95902. This is the exclusive method for opting out. After texting STOP to 95902, you will receive one additional message confirming that your request has been processed. 

6\. Alex and Ani reserves the right to remove subscribers from our messaging database at our discretion. For more information, text “HELP” to 95902, or contact us 800-725-7822. 

7\. In the event that you change or deactivate your mobile number, it is your responsibility to notify Alex and Ani to have your number changed or removed. 

8\. Alex and Ani and the mobile carriers will not be liable for any delays in the receipt of any SMS messages or undelivered messages. 

9\. Data obtained from you in connection with this SMS service may include your cell phone number, your carrier's name, the date, time and content of your messages and other information you provide to us as part of this service. We may use this information to contact you and to provide the services you request from us. 

10\. The Program is provided "as is" without any warranties of any kind. We assume no responsibility, and will not be liable, for technical, hardware, software or telephone malfunctions of any kind, lost or unavailable network connections, or failed, incorrect, incomplete, inaccurate, garbled or delayed electronic communications caused by or arising from your use of the program. 

11\. These terms and conditions are subject to change at any time without notice. 

###  Mobile Privacy 

Alex and Ani offers mobile applications (commonly known as "apps") and mobile-optimized experiences that allow you to shop online, check product availability, learn about store events, or receive other information from Alex and Ani. All personal information collected by Alex and Ani via our mobile application is protected by this Privacy Policy. 

Although you do not have to provide your location information to Alex and Ani to use our mobile applications, our store-specific services such as find-an-item require a zip code to function. You may manually enter a zip code and we will save your zip code(s) for future reference. Alternatively, when you download our mobile application, you may choose to allow it to obtain your precise location from your mobile device when you click the "near me" button. In this case, we will determine your zip code from the precise location data received from your mobile device. We do not store precise location data; we only store the zip code associated with the location. We may also update our mobile applications to offer automatic (or "push") notifications. We will provide push notifications only to those customers who opt-in to receive such notifications from Alex and Ani. If you have questions about location and notification privacy, please contact your mobile service provider or the manufacturer of your device to learn how to adjust your settings. 

In the future, we may offer updated or enhanced versions of our mobile applications that include additional features created by us or using third party functionality. Our applications or the third party may automatically collect information about your precise location from your device, but only if you allow it. 

###  Cookies, Web Beacons, and Other Similar Technologies 

Our Website uses "cookie" and "web beacon" technology. We use cookies and web beacons to distinguish you from other visitors, track your IP address and usage of our site, and to identify the name of the website from which you linked to alexandani.com. This information is used for fulfilling contracts with our business partners, and to help us serve you better by improving our website design, as well as our products, services, and promotions. We do not otherwise track any information about your use of other websites. Non-personally identifiable information obtained through cookies and web beacons may be shared with or obtained by service providers on our behalf. 

A cookie is a small data file that is placed on the hard drive of your computer when you visit a website. A "session cookie" expires immediately when you end your session (i.e., close your browser). A "persistent cookie" stores information on the hard drive so when you end your session and return to the same website at a later date, the cookie information is still available. A web beacon is a small string of code that represents a clear graphic image and is used in conjunction with a cookie. 

When you visit our Website, we may use both a session and a persistent cookie. This Alex and Ani-placed cookie may contain information (such as a unique user ID) that is used to track your usage of our Website and in some cases, your e-mail address. Your e-mail address is only saved in this Alex and Ani-placed cookie if you register with us. A web beacon allows us to capture certain additional types of information about a visitor's actions on a website, such as a visitor's cookie number, the time, date, duration and number of page views, a description of the page where the Web beacon is placed, and details about any items that were purchased. 

If you register with us, this Alex and Ani-placed cookie allows us to recognize you when you return to our Website and provides you with access to your account information. If you save your information with or order from us, we may also use cookies to monitor and maintain information about your use of our Website. If you have not saved your information with or ordered from us, we may monitor and maintain information about your use of our Website in a manner that does not identify you. You can disable cookies at any time by using your browser options; however, if you turn off cookies, we will not be able to track your order or enable you to make a purchase from our Website. In addition, we will not be able to recognize you as a registered user to allow you access to your account information. 

We may use Flash Cookies (also known as Local Stored Objects) or other similar technologies. A Flash cookie is a small data file placed on a computer using Adobe Flash technology that may be built into your computer or downloaded by you to your computer. We use these technologies to personalize and enhance your online experience, facilitate processes, personalize and store your settings. Flash cookies may help our website visitors to, for example, set volume preference associated with a video experience, play games and perform surveys. They help us improve our sites by measuring which areas are of greatest interest to customers. We do not use Flash cookies for marketing or behavioral targeting purposes. Flash cookies are different from browser cookies and the cookie management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies. Learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies. If you disable Flash cookies or other similar technologies, please be aware that you may not have access to certain features and services that make your online experience more efficient and enjoyable. 

###  Third-Party Advertising Partners 

We use third-party service providers to serve advertisements (banners or links) on our behalf across the Internet. 

These service providers may collect non-personally identifiable information about your visits to our Website, and your interaction with our products and services. Such non-personally identifiable information is anonymous and does not include your name, address, e-mail address or other personal information. The anonymous information is collected through the use of a pixel tag (also known as cookies and action tags), which is industry-standard technology used by most major websites. 

In addition to the anonymous information about your visits to our Website, our service providers may also use the anonymous information about your visits to other websites to target advertisements for products and services available from Alex and Ani. 

###  Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance 

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older. 

###  Links to Other Websites and Services 

Our Website may include links to other Internet sites, content, or videos (embedded or direct links) maintained by third parties ('Linked Sites'). Alex and Ani provides Linked Sites to you solely as a convenience, and the inclusion of Linked Sites does not imply endorsement by Alex and Ani of the Linked Sites. You access Linked Sites at your own risk and by accessing them you leave our Website. Linked Sites are not under the control of Alex and Ani and Alex and Ani is not responsible for the contents of any Linked Site, including the privacy policies or tracking technologies they may use. We encourage you to check the applicable privacy policy to determine how they will handle any personally identifying information they collect from you. 

###  Your Information, Your Choice 

To update us with your information-sharing preferences, you may contact us using one of the following methods: 

  * Call 401.633.1486, or 
  * E-mail info@alexandani.com 
  * Send your request to 2000 Chapel View Blvd. Suite 360, Cranston RI 02920 

###  Children's Privacy 

Our Website is not targeted for use by children under the age of 13 and Alex and Ani does not knowingly request or collect personal information from any person under 13 years of age without prior verifiable parental consent. 

If we become aware that an individual is under the age of 13 and has submitted any information to Alex and Ani for any purpose without prior verifiable parental consent, we will delete his or her information from our files. 

###  Security 

We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect the confidentiality and security of personally identifiable information transmitted to us using our Website. To guard your information, our Website uses Secure Sockets Layer (SSL). SSL encrypts your credit card number in transmission to our third party credit card processor. We do not store any credit card information on our servers. Please note that e-mail is not encrypted and is not considered to be a secure means of transmitting credit card information. 

To be sure your connection is secure, look at the bottom status bar of your browser window. If you see an unbroken key or a closed lock (depending on your browser) the SSL is active and your information is secure. Most browsers offer additional security alerts as well. 

###  Business Transitions 

As we continue to develop our business, we may undergo a business transition such as acquiring another company, merging with an existing company, or selling a portion of our assets. In such transitions, customer information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. In the unlikely event that Alex and Ani or substantially all of its assets are acquired or enter a court proceeding, you acknowledge that such transfers may occur and that your Personal Information can continue to be used as set forth in this Privacy Policy. 

###  Policy Changes 

This policy replaces all previous disclosures we may have provided you about our information practices. We reserve the right to change this policy, and to apply any changes to information previously collected, as permitted by law. If there are material changes to this policy or our information practices change in the future, we will notify you by posting the policy changes on our Website. 

###  ABOUT US 

We are Alex and Ani, LLC of 2000 Chapel View Boulevard, Suite 240, Cranston, RI 02920 (the “Company”, “we”, “our”, “us”) and we can be contacted regarding this privacy policy at customerservice@alexandani.com.

Our data protection officer is located in the United Kingdom and can be contacted at dataprotection@alexandani.com. 

###  UK / EU PRIVACY POLICY

CATEGORIES OF INFORMATION WE COLLECT 

We collect personal information from you such as your name, email address, billing address, shipping address, telephone number, credit card information and date of birth. In certain circumstances, we may also request photographic identification from you such as your driver’s licence, passport, military identification or student identification for example. 

###  HOW WE COLLECT YOUR INFORMATION 

We collect your personal information through communications with you, or through the Company website (our “Website”), whenever you interact with us online. Some examples include:

• registering for a shopping account on our Website

• requesting that merchandise be sent to you or others or to place an order

• purchasing products from our Website

We may also collect personal information about you from other third parties, such as demographic firms, to make our future service and marketing efforts more efficient and personalised for you. We also gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser information, Internet Service Provider (ISP), operating system, date/time stamps and clickstream data. 

###  WHY WE COLLECT YOUR INFORMATION 

We use your personal information to conduct our business and to provide you with the best possible products, services and experience. 

###  Who Else May Have Access to Your Information 

To best serve you, we may share your personal information with service providers that provide support services to us or that help us market our products and services. Service providers are third parties who perform services on our behalf. They are contractually restricted from using your information in any manner other than in helping us to provide you with the products and services available from the Company. We may also share your personal information with our business service providers so that we can provide our goods to you.

We may also disclose your personal information to a third party when you ask us to do so or when we believe it is required by law. 

###  Countries Having Access to Your Information 

For data storage reasons we are unable to store all of your personal information in the United Kingdom. Our servers, storing and keeping your information secure, are located in countries which have an adequate level of protection, or with which we have signed agreements incorporating the Model Contract Clauses.

We also have a number of Company staff members and service providers who are located in the United States of America. This means that your information can be accessed outside of the European Economic Area. However, to ensure your personal data is kept secure, we have signed agreements incorporating the Model Contract Clauses. 

###  YOUR CONSENT 

When you came to our Website, you were asked to tick a box confirming you have read this privacy policy and that you agree to us collecting your personal information and using it in the ways and for the reasons explained in this privacy policy. You can view this notice again by clicking here: https://www.alexandani.com/privacy-policy/ 

###  COLLECTING YOUR INFORMATION LEGALLY 

We are able to legally collect and use your personal information either because:

you have provided us with your consent to do so as explained above; and/or

collecting and using your personal information is necessary for us to:

• process any orders or requests made by you via our Website; or

• carry out our legitimate interests for direct marketing purposes. 

###  RETENTION OF YOUR INFORMATION 

We will only retain your personal information for as long as it is necessary to process your order, keep you up to date with Company products and promotions where you have asked us to do so and/or to provide you with the best customer experience possible. Processing is necessary for the purposes of Company’s legitimate interests (for example, to deal with any claims or queries which you have relating to your order), or where we are required to do so by law. 

###  YOUR RIGHTS 

You have the right to:

• be informed about the personal information we collect from you and use, which this privacy policy seeks to do;

• obtain confirmation from us that your personal information is being collected and used by us and to access the personal information held about you by us;

• have your personal information corrected if it is inaccurate or incomplete at any time;

• erasure, or the right to be forgotten, which means you can request deletion or removal of any personal information we hold about you at any time;

• block or suppress us collecting and using your personal information, which means we can continue to store your personal information but we cannot further collect or use it in any way;

• obtain and reuse any personal information we hold about you for your own purposes across different services, which allows you to move, copy or transfer your personal information easily from Company to another place notified by you to us in a safe and secure way without hindrance to the usability of your personal information; and

• object to us collecting or using your personal information where this is based on:

a legitimate interest or the performance of a task in the public interest; or

direct marketing

To make any requests as listed above, please contact us at dataprotection@alexandani.com.

We will confirm any requests relating to your rights above within one month of receipt of your request, or within two months of receipt of your request where this request is more complex. 

###  WITHDRAWAL OF YOUR CONSENT 

You can tell us to stop collecting and using your personal information at any time by emailing us at dataprotection@alexandani.com.

If you tell us to stop collecting and using your personal information, the consequences of doing so are that:

• you will be unable to make a purchase through our Website;

• we will be unable to update you on Company promotions and product news;

• we will be unable to provide you with the best user experience possible to our Website; and

• we will generally be unable to provide you with the best customer experience we would like to provide you with. 

###  MOBILE PRIVACY 

Company may offer mobile applications (commonly known as “apps”) and/or mobile-optimised experiences that allow you to shop online, check product availability, learn about store events, or receive other information from Company. All personal information collected by Company via our mobile application is protected by this Privacy Policy.

Although you do not have to provide your location information to us to use our mobile applications, our store-specific services, such as find-an-item require a postcode to function. You many manually enter a postcode and we will save your postcode(s) for future reference. Alternatively, when you download our mobile application, you may choose to allow it to obtain your precise location from your mobile device when you click the “near me” button. In this case, we will determine your postcode from the precise location data received from your mobile device. We do not store precise location data; we only store the postcode associated with the location. We may also update our mobile applications to offer automatic (or “push”) notifications. We will provide push notifications only to those customers who opt-in to receive such notifications from Company. If you have questions about location and notification privacy, please contact your mobile service provider of your device to learn how to adjust your settings.

In the future, we may offer updated or enhanced versions of our mobile applications that include additional features created by us or using third party functionality. Our applications or the third party may automatically collect information about your precise location from your device, but only if you allow it. 

###  COOKIES, WEB BEACONS, AND OTHER SIMILAR TECHNOLOGIES 

Our Website uses “cookie” and “web beacon” technology. We use cookies and web beacons to distinguish you from other visitors, track your IP address and usage of our site, and to indemnify the name of the website from which you linked to alexandani.com. This information is used for fulfilling contracts with our business partners, and to help us serve you better by improving our website design, as well as our products, services and promotions. We do not otherwise track any information about your use of other websites. Non-personal information or anonymised/pseudonymised information obtained through cookies and web beacons may be shared with or obtained by service providers on our behalf.

A cookie is a small data file that is placed on the hard drive of your computer when you visit a website. A “session cookie” expires immediately when you end your session (i.e., close your browser). A “persistent cookie” stores information on the hard drive so when you end your session and return to the same website at a later date, the cookie information is still available. A web beacon is a small string of code that represents a clear graphic image and is used in conjunction with a cookie.

When you visit our Website, we may use both a session and a persistent cookie. This Company-placed cookie may contain information ( such as a unique user ID) that is used to track your usage of our Website and in some cases, your email address. Your email address is only saved in this Company-placed cookie if you register with us. The web beacon allows us to capture certain additional types of information about a visit’s actions on a website, such as a visitor’s cookie number, the time, date, duration and number of page views, a description of the page where the Web beacon is placed, and the details about any items that were purchased.

If you register with us, this Company-placed cookie allows us to recognise you when you return to our Website and provides you with access to your account information. If you save your information with or order from us, we may also use cookies to monitor and maintain information about your use of our Website. If you have not saved your information with or ordered from us, we may monitor and maintain information about your use of our Website in a manner that does not identify you. You can disable cookies at any time by using your browser options; however, if you turn off cookies, we will not be able to track your order or enable you to make a purchase from our Website. In addition, we will not be able to recognise you as a registered user to allow you access to your account information. You can find out more about cookies by following this link: https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/online/cookies/.

We may use Flash Cookie (also known as Local Stored Objects) or other similar technologies. A Flash cookie is a small data file placed in a computer using Adobe Flash technology that may be built into your computer or downloaded by you to your computer. We use these technologies to personalise and enhance your online experience, facilitate processes, personalise and store your settings. Flash cookies may help our website visitors to, for example, set volume preference associated with a video experience, play games and perform surveys. They help us improve our sites by measuring which areas are of greatest interest to customers. We do not use Flash cookies for marketing or behavioural targeting purposes. Flash cookies are different from browser cookies and the cookie management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies. Learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies. If you disable Flash cookies or other similar technologies, please be aware that you may not have access to certain features and services that make your online experience more efficient and enjoyable. 

###  THIRD-PARTY ADVERTISING PARTNERS 

We use third-party service providers to serve advertisements (banners or links) on our behalf across the Internet.

These service providers may collect non-personal information or anonymised/pseudonymised information about your visits to our Website, and your interaction with our products and services. Such information is anonymous and does not include your name, address, email address or other personal information. The anonymous information is collected through the use of a pixel tag (also known as cookies and action tags), which is industry-standard technology used by most major websites.

In addition to the anonymous information about your visits to our Website, our service providers may also use the anonymous information about your visits to other websites to target advertisements for products and services available from Company. 

###  CHILDREN'S PRIVACY 

We do not knowingly collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.

If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on this Website or on or through any of its features/register on the Website, make any purchases through the Website or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number or email address.

If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13, we will delete that information.

If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at dataprotection@alexandani.com. 

###  LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES AND SERVICES 

Our Website may include links to other Internet sites, content, or videos (embedded or direct links) maintained by third parties (“Linked Sites”). Company provides Linked Sites to you solely as a convenience, and the inclusion of Linked Sites does not imply endorsement by Company of the Linked Sites. You access Linked Sites at your own risk and by accessing them you leave our Website. Linked Sites are not under the control of Company and Company is not responsible for the contents of any Linked Site, including the privacy policies or tracking technologies they may use. We encourage you to check the applicable privacy policy to determine how they will handle any personal information they collect from you. 

###  YOUR INFORMATION, YOUR CHOICE 

To update us with your information-sharing preferences, you may contact us using one of the following methods:

• send your request to 2000 Chapel View Blvd. Suite 360, Cranston RI 02920; or

• email dataprotection@alexandani.com. 

###  SECURITY 

We shall implement appropriate technical and organisational measures to ensure a level of security appropriate to potential risks, including:

• the pseudonymisation and encryption of your personal information where appropriate;

• ensuring ongoing confidentiality, integrity, availability and resilience of processing systems and services;

• ensuring we can restore access to personal information in a timely manner if a physical or technical incident occurs; and

• regular testing, assessment and evaluation of the effectiveness of our technical and organisational measures to ensure your personal information is secure.

We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect the confidentiality and security of personal information transmitted to us using our Website. To guard your information, our Website uses Secure Sockets Layer (“SSL”). SSL encrypts your credit card number in transmission to our third party credit card processor. We do not store any credit card information on our servers. Please note that email is not encrypted and is not considered to be a secure means of transmitting credit card information.

To be sure your connection is secure, look at the bottom status bar of your browser window. If you see an unbroken key or a closed lock (depending on your browser) the SSL is active and your information is secure. Most browsers offer additional security alerts as well. 

###  BUSINESS TRANSACTIONS 

As we continue to develop our business, we may undergo a business transition such as acquiring another company, merging with an existing company, or selling a portion of our assets. In such transitions, customer information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. In the unlikely event that Company or substantially all of its assets are acquired or enter a court proceeding, you acknowledge that such transfers may occur and that your personal information can continue to be used as set forth in this privacy policy. 

###  POLICY CHANGES 

This policy replaces all previous disclosures we may have provided you about our information practices. We reserve the right to change this policy, and to apply any changes to information previously collected, as permitted by law. If there are material changes to this policy or our information practices change in the future, we will notify you by posting the policy changes on our Website. 

###  DATA PROTECTION OFFICER AND MAKING A COMPLAINT 

We pride ourselves on excellent customer service, and if you have any questions about your data please reach out to our interim Data Protection Officer (DPO) Mario Baletta at dataprotection@alexandani.com. You can also contact the DPO to report any misuse or complaint about the way we have collected or used your personal information.

If you are unhappy about the way we have handled your complaint and/or you would like to take the matter further or make a complaint directly to our regulator without contacting us first, you can do so by contacting the Information Commissioner’s Office (“ICO”) by following this link: https://ico.org.uk/concerns/ or telephoning the ICO helpline, which is 0303 123 1113.
